<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://lexvar.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alex&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 22:06:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lexvar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://lexvar.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexvar.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Portuguese DevOps Engineer passionate about Linux, automation, self hosting and open source software.
I received my Bachelors in Computer Engineering from the University of Coimbra in 2018 and my Masters from Instituto Superior Técnico in 2021, with a specialization in Security. I am also experienced in low level C programming and cryptography.
My expertise     Linux (RHEL, Debian) Python, C, Bash, Java SQL, Git Ansible, Chef Terraform Docker, Docker Compose Kubernetes, OpenStack Gitlab CI, Github Actions AWS, Azure Prometheus, Consul, Vault  Certifications     Microsoft Azure Fundamentals  Awards &amp;amp; Projects     2nd place @ TecStorm 2019 Hackathon: Developed a mobile app, during 48 hours, to reduce the social isolation of elderly people, by providing a simple mechanism to send daily feedback to their family Critical Software SIW: Designed a system to provide information and warnings of noise levels in the workspace by collecting bluetooth sensor data on a Raspberry Pi and displaying it in leds and a web dashboard (Linux, Python, Flask) 2nd place @ ShiftAppens 2018 Hackathon: Created a mobile app aimed at enabling emergency reporting for people with disabilities through an intuitive interface which alerts the proper authorities Meetup App: Developed an app, with a team of 7 students, to connect local people with similar interests, by allowing users to create chats for each meet up or topic (Java, Firebase, Facebook API); Achieved 500 downloads on the Google Play store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder</title>
      <link>https://lexvar.github.io/posts/emgfa-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 22:06:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexvar.github.io/posts/emgfa-demo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://lexvar.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexvar.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me an e-mail to avalente@protonmail.com, or send a message to my linkedin.
Check out my projects in Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://lexvar.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lexvar.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to see here&amp;hellip; Move along!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
